麦琪:表示极度厌恶的六个字母单词.
Maggie: A six-letter word for extreme dislike.
杰森:麦琪!!我最讨厌填字游戏.
Jason: Maggie!I hate crossword puzzles.
我们结婚时你就知道的.不对,
As much today as when we first got married.No,no, hate isn't strong enough.
光是厌恶还不够.应该是憎恶才行.
I loathe them.
麦琪:憎恶,就是这个,谢谢.
Maggie: Loathe! That's it! Thanks.
杰森:何足挂齿.
Jason: Don't mention it.
麦琪:下面是阳希·德瑞格的印第安伙伴.
Maggie: Ok, the Indian sidekick of TV's Yancy Derringer.
杰森:不.
Jason: No.
麦琪:11个字母.
Maggie: Eleven letters.
杰森:不不不不不.
Jason: No, no, no, no, no.
【低语】
[Mumbles]
麦琪:你说什么
Maggie: What?
Jason: Pokohatiwah.That means, Wolf who stands in water.
And you would know these things
if you didn't spend all day on cross word puzzles
本:我要演戏了!我要演戏了!!我要演戏了!
Ben: I got a part! I got a part! I got a part!
麦琪:本,安静点!你说什么?
Maggie: Ben! Calm down.What are you talking about?
本:开萝尔学校里正准备上演一部戏剧,
Ben: The high school play that Carol's drama club is doing.
需要一个儿童演员,我和开萝尔起一去试镜,
I just went to the auditions with her and they needed a kid and I got
结果得到了这个角色.
the part!
麦琪:噢!恭喜恭喜!小南瓜
Maggie: Oh, congratulations, pumpkin!
杰森:这次你可出够风头了,本!
Jason: Yea, that's quite a coup, Ben!
六年级的小学生居然可以参加高中生的戏剧演出,了不起!!
Getting into the high school play from the sixth grade!
本:你们想不想看看我要演的角色?!
Ben: Want to hear my part?
麦琪:那当然,等等,让我坐好!
Maggie: Well, of course! Wait.Let me get comfortable.
杰森:耶!没错!我也坐好.开演吧,本!!
Jason: Yep, yep.Ok, me too.Here we go.Alright.
本:早上好,您要买报纸吗?我演的如何?
Ben: Morning.Do you want your paper now?Well?
杰森:果然很好,本!
Jason: That was terrific, Ben!
麦琪:嗯,很不错!!
Maggie: Oh, it sure was!
本:我还没好好排练呢,老爸老妈你们请等一下.
Ben: And I haven't even had any rehearsals yet, either.Just you wait.
杰森:那你先好好练练.
Jason: I don't know if I can.
本:早上好,您要买报纸吗?早上好,您要买报纸吗?
Ben: Morning.Do you want you paper now?Morning.Do you want your paper now?'
麦琪:亲爱的,你怎么了?
Maggie: Sweetheart, what's wrong?
开萝尔:今天在戏剧俱乐部的试镜真是没法说.
Carol: The drama club auditions today were a complete disaster.
那个可恶的莫妮卡把她好朋友带了过来,
Not only did I not get the lead because of Monica Shakelford called in
结果本来要我出演的重要角色给抢走了,最后只给我编排了微不足道的小角色,
a few favors, leaving me with a crummy little inky-dinky part,
整个事情都被她给整的乱了套……
and now the whole show is...
麦琪:着急也没用,开萝尔.
Maggie: Take a deep breath, Carol.
开萝尔:全砸了.
Carol: Ruined.
麦琪:怎么了?
Maggie: Why?
开萝尔:怎么了?你们知不知道这次谁出演男主角.
Carol: Why?Because who do you think got the romantic lead?
迈克:明日之星--迈克.
Mike: A star is born.
迈克:嘿!开萝尔,
Mike: Hey, let's face it, Carol.
你得面对事实!试镜结束后我演这个角色最合适不过.
I was the best person to audition for the part.
开萝尔:那是因为只有你一个人来参加试镜.
Carol: Mike, you were the only person.
迈克:那去哪里做什么?
Mike: What about Joey Scoffengerio?
开萝尔:乔伊·斯科芬瑞克想扮演另一个角色.
Carol: Joey Scoffengerio auditioned in a full body cast.
迈克:得了,
Mike: Ok, who's the best person for the part?
这个角色舍我其谁.
Who didn't have to be carried on stage?
开萝尔:得意什么?你连一句台词都背不出来.
Carol: See?He doesn't care one iota about this play.
麦琪:嗯,对了!!迈克,你几时对学校的戏剧这么感兴趣?
Maggie: Yea, Mike.Since when did you get interested in school plays?
杰森:却是让人难以索解!!
Jason: Or school period.
开萝尔:自从他知莫妮卡是女主角以后.
Carol: Since he found out Monica Shakelford was the leading lady.
麦琪和杰森:哦,原来如此.
Maggie and Jason: Ohh.
迈克:哪个莫妮卡.
Mike: Monica who?
开萝尔:就是那个让全校男生垂涎三尺的莫妮卡·希克福德?
Carol: Monica draws a whole crowd in her gym shorts Shakelford?
迈克:哦!没错,就是她--莫妮卡.活力四射的美女.
Mike: Oh, yes, yes.Monica.Healthy young adult.
麦琪:迈克,你参加学校剧团的演出,
Maggie: Mike if you're going to get involved in something like the school
应该是出于对戏剧的爱好,要是为了姑娘那就错了.
play you should be doing it for yourself.Not for some girl.This isn't right.
杰森:你妈妈说得没错,迈克.
Jason: It's true, Mike.
迈克:得了,爸爸你没见过莫妮卡.
Mike: Dad, you have not seen Monica.
杰森:嗯?!
Jason: Yea.I mean, yea.
我说是,你是为了接近姑娘才去演戏的,
You know, if you're just doing this to get next to some girl.
你这种态度就显得对戏剧这门艺术很不尊重.
That certainly isn't fair to the other kids who really care about the play.
迈克:行了,爸爸这是演戏,
Mike: Oh, come on, Dad.This is just acting.Any fool can do that.
我看连傻瓜都会演,
You just put some goop on your face and you say some junk that some stupid
只要在脸上抹点粉,在台上念念蹩脚作家写的台词.
writer wrote.
开萝尔:蹩脚作家?迈克,
Carol: Stupid writer?Mike this is Our Town by Thornton Wilder,
这部戏的作者是桑顿·怀尔德,他可是美国的大剧作家.
an American genius.
迈克:难不成他真是有名的大人物.
Mike: So, it's got big words.Big deal.
迈克:艾米丽,现在我已经决定好了,
Mike: Emily, I'm going to make up my mind right now.I won't go.
我决不离开你,今晚我就去跟保罗谈谈.
I'll tell Paul about it tonight.
波纳:乔治,你这又是何苦呢?
Boner: Why, George.I don't see why you have to.
迈克:波纳,你干嘛呢?
Mike: Bone.What're you doing?
波纳:帮你排戏呀!
Boner: I'm helping you learn your part.
迈克:你应该拿着剧本逐字逐句地好好念.
Mike: Just stick to your lines, ok?
波纳:乔治,我真不明白你为什么现在要做此决定.
Boner: Why, George, I don't see why you have to decide right now.
开萝尔:波纳,你在演艾米丽!真是没得说.
Carol: Boner's playing Emily?How perfect.
迈克:噢!是吗?比波纳更让人倒胃口的女主角难道没有吗?眼前的开萝尔不就是吗?
Mike: Oh, yea?Well, I can think of a lot of uglier leading ladies, Carol.
波纳:开萝尔说得没错!这活我可干不了.
Boner: Yea.Wait, I don't think I like that.
迈克:波纳,帮帮忙!!
Mike: Boner, come on.
我只是要莫妮卡知道,我很认真地对待此事,明白吗?
I want Monica to think that I have done some work on this, ok?
波纳:老实说我看得出,你对这部戏并不太喜欢.
Boner: You know, maybe the point of this play stuff is just to get to
wear makeup and tights
迈克:你别开玩笑了,
Mike: What?Are you kidding?
今晚全校最漂亮的姑娘要到我家里来,
I have got the hottest Hooterette at Dewey High coming to my house tonight.
我认为这部戏可谓万中选一.
This acting stuff is great.
迈克:艾米丽透过那扇窗,每天晚上我都能看到你,
Mike: Uh, Emily, from my window up there I can just see your head nights
看到你在做功课.
when you're doing your homework.
莫妮卡:真的?你天天都这么做?
Monica: Why, can you?
迈克:对,你念书真用功,艾米丽,你一定很喜欢学习.
Mike: Yea, you certainly do stick to it Emily.I guess you must like school.
莫妮卡:迈克,演戏也要流露真情才能演的好.
Monica: Mike, use what you're feeling.
迈克:嗯?!你要我现在就表达自己的内心深处的感情.
Mike: Uh, you mean like what I'm feeling right now?
莫妮卡:对,就这样才行!!
Monica: Yea, go with the moment.Let's see where were we.
刚才到哪了!!真是浪费时间.
Um, It passes the time.
迈克:嗯!好的,
Mike: Uh, well, Emily, what do you think?
艾米丽,你看怎么样,
We might work out a kind of telegraph from your window to mine.
不妨在你的窗口和我的窗口之间,互相打打电报,
And once in a while,
有的时候你不妨给我来一点暗示之类的,表示一下你的……
you could give me a kind of hint or two about one of those, uh...
莫妮卡:真是妙极了.
Monica: That was great!
迈克:嘿嘿,谢谢你.
Mike: Thank you.
莫妮卡:你已经进入了角色,甚至忘了台词来问我,
Monica: No, I mean you were so into character;
表演自然极了.
you just forgot the words and kissed me.Spontaneously.
迈克:是呀,这是我的内心真感情.
Mike: Yup, yea, that's what I did alright.
莫妮卡:你是充分发挥了你的感情.
Monica: That is a wonderful use of your instrument.
迈克:不,只能在戏里.
Mike: Uh, well, uh, listen.I gotta warn you this may happen again.
莫妮卡:噢!这样不行!剧本里可没这场.
Monica: Oh, no, cause see it's not in the script.
迈克:演戏时这样吻你好不好?
Mike: Hey, how about we go over that kissing scene on more time?
莫妮卡:可是本子上并没有.
Monica: We don't have our scripts.
迈克:可以创造嘛.
Mike: Eh, we can fake it.
杰森:回来的太晚了,是不是?
Jason: Kind of late for a school night isn't it?
迈克:对对,不过我不是在外面玩,而是跟莫妮卡在排戏.
Mike: Uh, yea, yea, but listen I wasn't out having fun I was rehearsing with
Monica
杰森:开萝尔和本早在两个小时前就回来了.
Jason: Carol and Ben got home two hours ago.
迈克:嗯,并不是非得在学校大礼堂里排练的.
Mike: Well, not all rehearsing takes place in that auditorium.
杰森:那你们在哪排的呢?
Jason: Well, where did this one take place?
迈克:在哪排其实并不重要,
Mike: Uh, well, where really isn't important Dad.
最重要的是我们挖掘了潜台词,
See, what's important is that we explored the subtext and the internal
以及丰富的内在感情.
rhythms of the...
杰森:到底在哪,迈克?
Jason: Where, Mike?
迈克:在我车里.
Mike: In my car.
杰森:迈克,
Jason: Mike, I don't know,
你是不是同意这种说法,你在那个所谓的潜台词上面下的功夫太多,
but don't you suppose maybe you and Monica are spending a little too much
而在真正的台词上下的功夫极少.
time exploring the subtext and not quite enough time on the text?
迈克:哪又如何?
Mike: Huh?
杰森:开萝尔说你连台词都背不出来,
Jason: Well, Carol says you haven't even memorized your lines yet.
你想不想上台,
Come on, Mike, don't you want to try?
你想不想干出点名堂来,你除了姑娘以外,
Wouldn't you like to be really good at something?
还应该有更重要的事.
There's more to life, Mike, than making time with girls.
迈克:行了,爸爸,
Mike: Oh, come on, Dad.
我跟莫妮卡还没正式约会过呢.
Monica and I have not even been out on a date, yet.
杰森:这半个月里你每天晚上都跟她呆在一起.
Jason: You've been with her every night for the past two weeks.
迈克:爸爸,
Mike: Dad, I certainly do not call parking with a girl on a lonely dirt
我认为不能把跟一个姑娘坐在汽车里就叫做约会.
road a date.
迈克:我昨天一直在那座矮墙边上等着你.
Mike: Uh, I was, yesterday I was waiting for you over by the wall and,
你...
um, you...
莫妮卡:你走了.
Monica: Walked.
迈克:你走了.你回家了.
Mike: You walked, you walked home.
莫妮卡:回家,你回家了.
Monica: You really should know this by now.
老师:行了,迈克·西维尔,
Teacher: Time out! That's it, Seaver.Read my lips.We open tomorrow night.
你看着我,我们明晚正式演出,到时候有1000人来观看演出.
There are going to be a thousand people filling these seats.
迈克:1000人???
Mike: A thousand people?
老师:这算对了,笨蛋.
Teacher: That's right, chucklehead.
也许你不怕人家笑你,可我不愿意让人来笑话我,
Maybe you don't mind them laughing at you but I certainly don't want them
我是很要面子的.会有1000人.好吧,
laughing at me.I'm a sensitive artist.Alright, everybody take five.
大家休息5分钟.听着,
Oh, look Seaver.I'm sorry I yelled at you but I've been a little bit nervous.
迈克,我刚才对你嚷嚷,
I never directed a play before and there's a lot of people on the Hooter
是我心里太紧张了,我从来也没有导演过戏,我们学校里有这么一伙人,
faculty who'd like to see the old coach fall on his kiester with this one.
存心要看我这个教练出身的语文教师出洋相,他们认为我对文艺屁也不懂,
They think I got no business messing with arts.
我要出这口气,你给我好好的演.
But I'm going to prove them wrong.Give it all you got, kid.
迈克:1000人??
Mike: A thousand people?
迈克:艾米丽,要是我今后真有很大的转变,
Mike: Emily, if I do improve and make a big change, then would you be,
那么你能不能,我是说你肯不肯……演得怎么样?
I mean could you be... There how was that?
波纳:好得不能再好了.
Boner: You never been better.
迈克:这次死定了.两小时后,
Mike: Oh, gosh.That is it.I'm dead.
我就要在大众面前丢人现眼,爸妈和开萝尔他们说得没错.我的确是个呆瓜,
I'm two hours away from total public humiliation and everybody's right.
头脑简单的笨蛋,一无是处的废物.
I'm a goof off, a bozo, and a loser.
波纳:那谁又不是?
Boner: Hey, who isn't?
开萝尔:马上得走了,晚上七点之前全部演员都得去报到.
Carol: Mike, we should leave soon.We have to backstage by seven.
迈克:你先去,再让我练几分钟.
Mike: No, we don't have to leave for another five...
开萝尔:真是有意思,迈克!太有趣了,今天晚上就看谁笑了.
Carol: Oh, funny, Mike.Real funny.But we'll see who's laughing tonight.
迈克:波纳,你说我怎么会把自己弄到如此境地??
Mike: Oh, Bone.How did I get myself into this?
波纳:你本来就是个蠢才,所以这没什么好奇怪的.
Boner: You're stupid.
迈克:那你干嘛这么得意,波纳?!
Mike: What're you so calm for, you know?
你是五十步笑百步,比我更蠢的人就是你了,你还好意思笑我.
I mean, if there's anyone who's worse off than me, it's you.It's always you.
波纳:这次可不是.
Boner: Not this time.
迈克:何解?
Mike: What?
波纳:老实说,我也害怕忘记台词,
Boner: Hey, I was scared I would forget my lines, too.
可我后来想出了个绝招,
Then I came up with my brilliant plan.See this?
你看,
I got all my lines recorded on it.
我把台词都录进去了,我要是记不住,
So if I forget them,
就放录音,同时嘴巴也跟着动,
all I have to do is play the tape real loud and move my lips to
我从假戏真做里学来的.
it.I got the idea from watching Put It On the Hits.
录音机:测试,一二三四,开始啦.
Recorder: Testing.One.Two.Three.Four.Here we go!
波纳:你看怎么样?
Boner: What do you think?
迈克:波纳,士别三日,刮目相看,了不起!!
Mike: You know, Bone, you get more and more strange every year.
波纳:谢谢.
Boner: Thanks.
迈克:我要是病了,他们总不成逼我上台演戏吧.
Mike: I mean, I wouldn't even have to go on if I was hurt or something.
对了,波纳,太妙了,
Hey! Hey, that's it! Bone, oh, oh, great!
好,我走的时候,
Um, ok, just as we're starting to leave,
就在楼梯上摔一跤,装成把脚摔坏了,对,
I'm going to fall down the stairs and fake a broken leg.
你做我证人,你看怎么样.
Yea, Bone you'll be my witness, ok?What do you say?
录音机:好了,你们大家知道,我们是市政管理委员会委任的.
Recorder: Well, I don't have to tell you that we are run by a board
of select men
迈克:把那破玩意先关了行不行?
Mike: Oh, Would you turn that thing off?
录音机:所有年满21岁的男人,都有选举权.
Recorder: At the age of 21.Women vote in the...
杰森:波纳,你胳肢窝居然能发出声音来,了不起??
Jason: Is your voice coming from your armpit?
波纳:是的.车里见好么?
Boner: Yea! Hey, I'll meet you in the car, ok?
迈克:好.
Mike: Ok.
杰森:祝你好运,波纳.
Jason: Good luck, Boner.
波纳:我不靠这玩意儿.
Boner: Hey, I don't need luck.
麦琪:迈克,你走以前,
Maggie: Mike, before you leave,
我们要告诉你,我们都爱你,可对你要求不高.
we just wanted you to know that we love you and we're not expecting much.
杰森:麦琪.
Jason: Maggie.
麦琪:不不不,不是这意思,
Maggie: No, no, no.I didn't mean it.
我是想说不要失望,别盼着出奇迹,等等.
I just meant, don't despair, a miracle could happen.No, wait.
杰森:我们是你最坚强的后盾,迈克.
Jason: We're behind you, Mike.
麦琪:你只要踏上舞台以后,就千万不能再紧张,
Maggie: As soon as you step out on that stage you won't have time to be
你想到的是多少人在台下,
nervous.All that will matter is those hundreds of people,
坐在观众席上,抬着头看你的演出.
sitting in the audience, hanging on your every word.
迈克:喔,不!
Mike: Oh, no.
杰森:迈克,
Jason: Mike, look, before we completely undermine your confidence,
你一定要充满信心地走上舞台,我们都在台下看你的演出,
I want you to know your mom and I are going to be there,
到时候我们都会喝彩的.
we're going to be rooting for you.
杰森:爸爸是这么回事,刚才我从楼上下来的时候,
Mike: Well, see I don't know, Dad, see,
一不小心把腿……
just now when I was coming down the stairs I kind of...
开萝尔:迈克,快点,就等你了.
Carol: Mike, we have to go.
杰森:开萝尔,我想跟你说.
Jason: Carol, I just want you to know...
开萝尔:我知道,为我感到自豪,
Carol: I know.You're proud of me,
可事实上我今天是跑龙套的,
but the truth is it's a stinking little part and you're only going because
做父母的不得不来捧场,所以别说了.
you think you have to go, so let's go.
麦琪:快点穿衣服,别去的太晚了.
Maggie: Honey, go get dressed, we don't want to be late.
杰森:演完戏见,迈克.
Jason: See you after the show, Mike.
迈克:这……我觉得……觉得…
Mike: Speaking of the show, you know, I don't know, I just kind of, um...
杰森:嘿,本.
Jason: Hey, Ben!
本:早上好,您要买报纸吗?
Ben: Morning.Do you want your paper now?
杰森:别装了,迈克.
Jason: Break a leg, Mike!
巴瑞:还有五分钟,五分钟以后开幕.
Barry: Five minutes! Five minutes to curtain!
老师:注意了,注意了,我想最后再把戏稍微改动一下,
Teacher: Alright, I got a few last minute blocking changes here for you ok?
好吗?里奇,第17页,
Ritchie, page 17 I want you to head out towards the trellis here and
你刚出来就朝葡萄棚走,然后向右转,
buttonhook right.Carol, I want you to lead the schoolchildren in a wedge
开萝尔,你带一群小学生走中间,是这个位置,
up the middle here, clearing the whole left side,
把左边让出来,让黛比和雪莉跑进场,懂吗?
for Debbie and Shelly's entrance.You got that?
【众演员立刻开始叽叽喳喳】
[Everybody starts talking at once]
老师:好吧!好吧!
Teacher: Alright, alright, forget all that!
那就不改了,这么走上台去演,好好演,
Just go out there and kick them in the, uh Grab them by the...
要演得使观众目瞪口呆,懂吗?
Just go out there and act your fannies off ok?
巴瑞:现在离开演还有4分钟20秒.
Barry: Four minutes and twenty seconds! Four minutes and twenty seconds!
迈克:吆!吆!巴瑞!巴瑞我的好哥们.
Mike: Yo, yo, Barry my man!
巴瑞:有事没?
Barry: What?
迈克:你每次排戏都在,所有台词你肯定都会背,
Mike: Listen, you, you've been to all the rehearsals, right?
是不是?
So you probably know everybody's part by heart.
巴瑞:怎么?
Barry: Why?
迈克:我是随便问一句.
Mike: Well, I'm just curious.
巴瑞:哦.
Barry: Oh.
迈克:所以这的每一个角色,你都能顶得上去,
Mike: So, so, this means that you could probably, like, go on for any of us,
比如我,要是在开演之前,
even, uh, say, uh, me, if like, uh,
我突然得了病!看来他也不同意.
the last minute there was some I guess that's a no.
杰森:本·西维尔首次参加德维戏剧俱乐部的演出,他曾经演过空中狼,
Jason: Ben Seaver makes his debut at the Dewey Greasepaint Society,
比为剧场和福尔摩斯.
after appearances on Air wolf, Pee Wee's Playhouse and the Cosby Show?
麦琪:演员都这副德行,老是把自己吹得跟多么了不起.
Maggie: All actors lie about their credits.
杰森,要是假报火警会受到什么处罚?
Oh, Jason, what's the penalty for setting off a false fire alarm?
杰森:怎么?
Jason: Why?
麦琪:我担心迈克今天要丑态百出.
Maggie: I'm worried about Mike making a fool out of himself.
杰森:亲爱的,用不着假报火警破坏演出,
Jason: Honey, there's no need to disrupt the play with any false fire alarms.
我早就做好到时候昏倒在地的准备.
I'm fully prepared to faint.
学生:这是新罕布什尔州绿林之角,就在麻萨诸塞州边上.
Student: The name of the town is Grover's Corners, New Hampshire.
这第一幕是镇上的一天,
Just across the Massachusetts line.The first act shows a day in our town.
时间是黎明前.东方的天空开始出现,
The time is just before dawn.
开始出现一些曙光,
The sky is beginning to show some streaks of light over in the east there.
上帝.黎明有这么……
The morning star always gets...
学生:衣服我给你烫好了.
Student: I wash and iron the blue thing for you special.
开萝尔:妈,我不想穿这个.
Carol: But, Ma, I hate that dress.
学生:你给我轻点.
Student: Oh, hush up with you!
老师:幸亏让他往那走.
Teacher: Good thing I had her go long there.
旁白:韦伯先生是我们的发行人兼主编,
Narrator: Mr.Webb is publisher and editor of The Corner Sentinel,
这是我们本地的报纸.
that's our local paper, you know.
波纳:好了,你们知道我们是市政府委员会委任的,
Boner: Well, I don't have to tell you that we are run by a board of
所有男人年满21岁的男人…
select men.All men vote at the age of... of...
录音机:好了,你们知道我们是市政府委员会委任的...
Recorder: Well, I don't have to tell you that we are run by a board
of select
本:早上好,您要买报纸吗?
Ben: Morning.You want your paper now?
本:早上好,你现在要,你是要草纸?
Ben: Morning.Do you want your, um, your elbow now?
麦琪和杰森:报纸!本!报纸!!
Maggie and Jason: Paper! Ben! Paper!
学生:没错,我想买报纸.
Student: Yes, I'd love my paper now!
老师:吆!该你上了.能否成功,全在你身上了,
Teacher: Yo, Seaver, you're on.So far we got a hit on our hands.
你要是出乱子,就全砸了,就看你的了.
Screw up and you're a dead man.Have fun with it.
莫妮卡:说你好,艾米丽.
Monica: Hello, Emily.
迈克:你好,艾米丽.
Mike: Uh, hello, Emily.
莫妮卡:你好.
Monica: Oh, hello.
迈克:你昨天在班上的发言,真是太好了.
Mike: You know, you made a fine speech in class yesterday.
莫妮卡:昨天我本来准备的是谈门罗主义的,可是后来老师要我改谈林肯在葛底斯堡发表的演说,两个题都花了我不少时间.
Monica: Well, I was really ready to make a speech about the Monroe Doctrine,
but at the last minute Ms.
Cochran made me talk about the Louisiana Purchase instead.
I worked an awful long time on both of them.
迈克:每天晚上我都能看见你在做功课.
Mike: You know, I can just see your head nights when you're doing your
homework.
莫妮卡:真的?你为什么要这么做?
Monica: Why, can you?
迈克:你真是用功啊,艾米丽,你一定很爱学习.
Mike: You certainly do stick to it, Emily.I guess you must like school.
莫妮卡:我觉得这是每个人都得经历的事情.
Monica: Well, I feel it's something you have to go through.
迈克:我也这么看.
Mike: Yea.
莫妮卡:虚度光阴.
Monica: It passes the time.
迈克:我说艾米丽,
Mike: You know, Emily,
我能否在你的窗户和我的窗户之间打电报,在有的时候,
maybe we could work out a kind of telegraph from your window to mine?
比如在某一些数目题目上,
And every once in a while,
你给我来一点暗示,我不是要答案,
you could maybe give me a hint or two about one of those algebra problems?
就要那么点暗示.
Not the answer, but just some little hint?
杰森:麦琪,你瞧瞧,他居然……
Jason: Maggie, he's...
麦琪:真没想到!
Maggie: Great.
莫妮卡:我觉得这也是很重要的.
Monica: Well, I think it's awfully important, too.
迈克:艾米丽?
Mike: Emily?
莫妮卡:什么,乔治?
Monica: Yes, George?
迈克:要是我今后真的有很大的转变,你能不能,
Mike: If I do improve and make a big change, would you be, I mean,
我是说你肯不肯……
could you be...
莫妮卡:我答应你,我现在就答应你.
Monica: I am now.I always have been.
迈克:我觉得我们今天的谈话很重要.
Mike: So I guess this is as pretty important talk we've been having.
莫妮卡:是的,是的.
Monica: Yes.Yes.
迈克:你等一下,让我送你回家好吗?
Mike: You just wait here a minute and I'll walk you home, ok?
杰森:嘿,那是我儿子,他就是我的儿子!!
Jason: That's my boy! My son right up there! Come on!
开萝尔:迈克,你演得太棒了,我真没想到.
Carol: Mike, you were so good! I can't believe it!
迈克:是吗?
Mike: Was I?
开萝尔:对,我都快替你紧张死了.
Carol: Yea, and it really gets me tense, too.
莫妮卡:迈克,排戏时你怎么就那么拉不开?
Monica: Hey! Why were you holding back so much at all the rehearsals?
迈克:我不知道.
Mike: I don't know.
莫妮卡:怎么不跟我说.
Monica: Why didn't you tell me?
迈克:我不知道.
Mike: I don't know.
莫妮卡:迈克,是否还带我坐你的车.
Monica: Mike, um, are you going to the cast party later?
迈克:我不知道.
Mike: I don't know.
麦琪:那不是开萝尔麻!?
Maggie: There's Carol!
杰森:亲爱的你演得棒极了.
Jason: Honey, you were wonderful!
开萝尔:谢谢,对不起,我得去把戏服换掉,回见.
Carol: Oh, well, thanks.Well, excuse me, but I got to go take off my
freckles.Bye
麦琪:本过来了.
Maggie: And oh, there's Ben!
杰森:嘿!我的报童.
Jason: Hey! My paper boy!
麦琪:噢!你演得真是好极了.
Maggie: Oh, gosh, Ben, you were terrific!
本:拿我开心呢吧?全都让我搞的一团糟.
Ben: Are you kidding?I messed up.
开萝尔:是吗,我怎么一点也看不出来,是吗亲爱的.
Carol: Oh, really?Well, we didn't notice a thing, right, honey?
杰森:对.
Jason: No.
本:嗯,我试着好好掩饰过去.
Ben: Well, I did try to cover.
杰森:你演得的确出色.
Jason: And you did a masterful job at it.
本:喔.
Ben: Oh!
杰森:另一位明日之星去哪里了?
Jason: So, uh, where's our other star?
本:那么还有一位明星呢.
Ben: What other star?
杰森:迈克,你在这干什么,我们到处在找你呢.
Jason: Mike! What are you doing out here?We've been looking all over for you!
迈克:嗨!
Mike: Hi.
麦琪:大家都在谈论你的演技呢.
Maggie: Everybody's talking about you!
杰森:今天就属你演得最成功了.
Jason: You were the hit of the show!
麦琪:我知道你会成功的.
Maggie: I knew you could do it!
迈克:我真没想到.
Mike: I didn't.
杰森:这下该高兴了吧?
Jason: Big night for you, huh?
迈克:是的,我想是的.
Mike: Yea, I guess.
麦琪:你想什么,迈克.
Maggie: What's the matter, Mike?
迈克:我能问个问题吗.
Mike: Can I ask you guys something?
杰森:当然.
Jason: Sure.
迈克:我真的演的好?
Mike: Was I really good?
杰森:是呀.
Jason: Yes!
麦琪:真的.
Maggie: Yes!
迈克:是不是真的真的好.
Mike: No, I mean, really, really good?
杰森:我从来没有像今天晚上这样为你感到自豪.
Jason: Mike, I've never been more proud of you than I am tonight.
迈克:现在我倒感到害怕了,知道吗?
Mike: It's kind of scary.
过去我从来没有这种感觉,过去不管对什么,
See, I don't know, I've never really felt like this before.
我一向都不肯去努力,
See, I usually don't try that hard at being good at things because I just
因为算了,还是不谈这些了,
don't.But, um, I mean, just between you and me,
不过这话只对你讲,在很多事情上我常会出点洋相.
in a lot of things I kind of just goof off a little bit.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:不.
Jason: No.
迈克:是的,是的,
Mike: Yea, yea.But see, tonight, it was different.
不过今天晚上就不一样了,当我在舞台上时,
When I stepped out on that stage,
我完全忘掉台下的1000多名观众,忘了台上的一切,
I totally forgot that you guys were even out there.
甚至忘了波纳和他的录音机,
And about everything that was going wrong.
就觉得自己好像就是乔治,活生生地呆在那小镇里,
And forgot about Boner's stupid tape recorder.
总之,觉得演戏并没有事先想得那么难以企及.
I just felt like this guy named George in this little town.It was easy.
杰森:能在某方面表现出色一点,值得庆幸,迈克.
Jason: Being good at something is fun, Mike.
迈克:正如你们所说,
Mike: Is this what you meant all those times that you said that I should
我终于找到了自己的强项.
find something that I'm good at and do it?
杰森:没错.
Jason: Kind of.
麦琪:做的不错,像我的儿子.
Maggie: Exactly.
迈克:我整个人还行,并不是一无是处,对吗?
Mike: I was ok, wasn't I?
麦琪:你该出去一下,迈克,观众都等着要好好为你庆祝呢.
Maggie: You should go inside, Mike.There's a lot of people waiting to see you.
迈克:你们先走吧,我一会就来.好么?
Mike: You guys go ahead in.I need a minute, ok?
麦琪:好儿子!
Maggie: My baby.
Jason: I'm Jason Seaver! I'm Mike's father! Mike: Me, good at something
天晓得?00:22:42,100
Who knew?